K Rajender Babu

Mobile: 9014471234

Email: krbabu243@gmail.com

Career Profile

11.8 years of experience in software application development using UI, UX, Web design and Visual Design skills. Trained for Design thinking and Agile Methodology, Experienced in interacting with Design, Product, and Engineering teams to create user friendly interfaces. Extremely passionate and enthusiastic about staying up with the latest design trends that happen in the industry. As an individual to design, maintain and provide on-going technical knowledge and production of Desktop and Mobile applications. Ensuring the accessibility, usability and pixel perfection of the designs is to the highest standard. Self-organized, an obsession for consistency and optimistic.

Professional Strengths

- Possess extensive knowledge of design elements like color and composition
- Ability to present ideas in an effective manner
- · Ability to solve complicated problems
- Mock up wireframes, prototyping, storyboard
- · In-depth knowledge of Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator
- · Ability to meet deadlines and work under pressure
- Possess good organizational and management skills
- Creative and possess good artistic skills
- Strong visual eye and a natural attention to detail
- Experienced in interacting with design, product, and to create user friendly interfaces exhibiting a strong visual design sense with a focus on purpose driven interfaces, and an eye for good typography, composition, and use of color

Technology

| Hardware | Programming Languages | Multimedia/Graphic Tools |
|---------------|--------------------------|--------------------------|
| Windows / Mac | Web Technologies : | Adobe Photoshop CS6 |
| | HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap | Adobe Illustrator |
| | | Adobe Flash |
| | | Adobe Dreamweaver CS5 |

Qualifications

| Degree and Date | Institute | Major and Specialization |
|-----------------------|-------------------|----------------------------|
| Bachelor of Commerce | MKU - Madurai | Computer Application |
| Diploma in Multimedia | Karan Institute - | Diploma in Graphic and Web |
| 2006 | Hyderabad | designing |

Work Experience

| Organization | Tenure | Role |
|---------------------------|----------------------|------------------|
| Freelancer | Feb 2019 – Till Date | UX Designer |
| Tata Consultancy Services | Jun 2015 – Jan 2019 | UX Designer |
| Hibu India Pvt Ltd | Feb 2007 – Jun 2015 | Graphic Designer |

Assignments

The details of the various assignments that I have handled are listed here, in chronological order.

Key Assignments in TCS

| Project | TBU (technology business unit) | |
|-------------|--|--|
| Customers | RxC Digital Rewrite – USA, Intel, Infineon, TTD, ICICI, Nokia, Ericsson, Salestia Etc | |
| Period | June 2015 – Jan 2019 | |
| | (Offshore, Hyderabad) | |
| Description | Wireframs, Prototyping, Designing and implementing low to high-fidelity clickable mockups of the product, Android, iOS mobile app design, POC Designs. | |
| Role | UX Designer | |
| Tools Used | Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator | |
| Highlights | Role Highlights | |
| | Understanding project Requirement | |
| | Designed various screen's for different persons need. | |
| | Designed visual feel and layouts for different applications using adobe tools. | |

Key Assignments in HIBU

| Project | UK Premium Websites |
|-------------|---|
| Customer | Yell - UK |
| Period | Feb 2007 – June 2015 |
| Description | Web design agency online advertising strategy to suit it perfectly. From mobile-friendly web design in local small and medium business in UK. |
| Role | Graphic Designer |
| Tools Used | Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator |
| Highlights | As per the Client requirement designing web templates Design and Development of the corporate WebPages. Development of User Interfaces using Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator |

Major Achievements

Received couple of customer appreciations for designing web Applications as per customer expectations.

Received Pat on Back award consistently for three months.

Received consistently for 3 years appreciations mail from Management Best designing web Application in MWC (Mobile World Congress).

Personal Details

| Date of Birth | 21-12-1981 |
|-----------------|---------------------------|
| Nationality | Indian |
| Marital Status | Married |
| Languages Known | English, Hindi and Telugu |
| Sex | Male |